Juan Lagunas

Junior Frontend Developer

I am a self-taught frontend developer with over two years of focused learning driven by a passion for creating user-centric web projects that adhere to best practices and design standards. I have created a variety of practical, real-world projects, including designing and deploying a website for my own business. Furthermore, my background in education, customer service, and entrepreneurship brings with it a well-rounded approach to problem-solving and team collaboration. I am eager to apply my diverse experiences and strong dedication to mastering frontend development in a professional setting.

✓ dev.jlagunas@gmail.com

(234) 567-8900

San Diego, CA

Portfolio

PROJECTS

Cafe Triangle

10/2023 to 12/2023

This is the website for the local cafe I owned in Ishikawa, Japan, a static site that was carefully crafted with a user-centric, responsive design. The site features optimized images for faster load times, lazy loading for improved performance, and a seamless browsing experience across devices. Live Site

Made width: ▶ Angular ▶ Typescript ▶ Tailwind CSS ▶ Flowbite

Features: ▶ Multi-lingual ▶ Dark/Light Modes

Responsive DesignOptimized Images

Code Chicano 10/2023 to 12/2023

Code Chicano is a fully functional C.R.U.D. application powered by Firebase as its backend. The application features an integrated Quill editor, allowing login and the ability to create and publish new blog posts at any time. The blog is fully responsive, offering a range of advanced features and functionality designed to enhance the experience. Live Site

Made with: ▶ Angular ▶ Angular Material ▶ SCSS ▶ Firebase ▶ Typescript

Features: ▶ Firebase Authentication ▶ Firebase Database

Quill EditorDark/Light Modes

Cosmic Neighborhood

10/2023 to 12/2023

Cosmic Neighborhood is an expanded and enhanced version of a Frontend Mentor challenge, offering users an interactive and informative exploration of our solar system's planets. A standout feature of this project is the use of Three.js to create interactive 3D models of the planets, allowing users to zoom in, view them from various angles, and engage with the models for a dynamic and immersive experience. Live Site

Made with: ▶ Vue ▶ Javascript ▶ Tailwind CSS ▶ Three JS

Features: ▶ 3D planet models ▶ Interactive U.I.

Responsive DesignCSS Animations

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cafe Owner

Cafe Owner

Cafe Owner

Managed daily operations, designed the cafe's website, and implemented strategies to improve customer satisfaction and operational efficiency.

Hakusan City Board of Education 03/2020 to 03/2021

Assisted in planning and delivering engaging lessons to students of various ages and proficiency levels.

Aeon Corporation 07/2015 to 02/2019

Taught students of various ages using Aeon curriculum, helping them reach clear and measurable goals.

Viejas Casino and Resort 10/2006 to 01/2013

VIP ConciergeKept strong interpersonal relationships with all guests while providing great service in a fun and professional manner.

SKILLS

Javascript
HTML5
CSS3
SASS
Tailwind CSS
Angular
Vue
Git
UX/UI Design

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Scroll Gallery

03/2024 to 04/2024

A horizontal scroll gallery made with vanilla javascript displaying my photography and filled with GSAP scroll animations. Live Site

Portfolio Site

03/2024 to 04/2024 My portfolio site made with Vue and Tailwind CSS. Prominent features include Vue I18n translations, responsive design, and dark/light modes. Live Site

Vue Text Tutorial

03/2024 to 04/2024 A comprehensive tex

A comprehensive text based Vue tutorial filled with examples that focus on beginner friendly explanations of the most important Vue concepts. <u>Live Site</u>

Angular Text Tutorial

03/2024 to 04/2024 A comprehensive text based Angular tutorial. <u>Live Site</u>

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Arts in

Linguistics

University of California, San Diego 12/2012 to 06/2015

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish, Japanese (business level)